Rudyard Kipling Collection
Rudyard Kipling Collection
1874-1964
Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.
16.5 linear ft.
Papers of the British author, novelist, poet, journalist. Includes correspondence, writings, and memorabilia of Kipling himself, well as research material from a number of private collections. Kipling material consists of correspondence, totaling over 950 items (over 750 authored by Kipling); writings, including manuscript (handwritten and typed) and published versions of Kipling's prose, speeches, verse and dramatic works; memorabilia (legal material, photographs, portraits and caricatures); printed materials; writings by others; and miscellany. The private collections consist of Kipling material formerly owned by H.H. and S.S. McClure, E.W. Martindell, and Alan D. Wilson.
4199969
Biographical History
Joseph Rudyard Kipling (1865-1936) was an English author and poet. His best-known works include the novels and short story collections The Jungle Book (1894), Just So Stories (1902), Puck of Pook's Hill (1906), and Kim (1901), as well as a number of poems such as "Mandalay" (1890), "Gunga Din" (1890), and "If--" (1910).
Kipling was born in Bombay, India, into an artistic family: his father was a sculptor, pottery designer, and professor of architectural sculpture and two of his aunts were married to painters (Georgiana to Edward Burne-Jones and Agnes to Edward Poynter). At the age of six and he his sister were sent back to England to school, as was common with the children of British colonial India. After six unsatisfactory years with a Mr. and Mrs. Holloway, Rudyard and Trix were taken in by their aunt Georgiana.
Kipling attended the United Services College in Devon and then went to Lahore in what is now Pakistan to become assistant editor of a small newspaper. In addition to editing, Kipling contributed a great many stories to the paper (approximately 39 in one year) and several travel sketches. In 1889 Kipling returned to London via a roundabout eight-month journey that took him to Rangoon, Singapore, Hong Kong and Japan, and various cities in the United States and Canada. Upon his arrival in London he began building a reputation as a writer, publishing two novels in two years along with several short stories.
In 1892 Kipling married Carrie Balestier and shortly thereafter the couple moved to the United States, settling in Vermont, where Kipling began writing the Jungle Book stories and produced four novels in four years. In July 1899, despite their pleasant life in Vermont, Kipling decided to return to England and came to Torquay on the Devon coast. Kipling soon earned a reputation as "the poet of the Empire" and when he and his family paid a Christmas visit to the British colonies in South Africa (which became an annual tradition) they were warmly received.
In 1907 Kipling was awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature "in consideration of the power of observation, originality of imagination, virility of ideas and remarkable talent for narration which characterize the creations of this world-famous author," becoming the first English-language recipient.
After World War I, during which Kipling's only son John was killed, he wrote (1923) a two-volume history of his son's regiment, the Irish Guards, which is considered to be one of the finest examples of regimental history. He also became a "roving correspondent" for the British press. Among his other occupations, in 1922 he developed "The Ritual of the Calling of an Engineer" for the University of Toronto, a statement of duties and responsibilities to be recited by graduates in engineering; the ritual is sometimes called the Kipling Ritual and is still in use today. In 1925 he became Lord Rector of St. Andrews University in Scotland, though his writing began to slow somewhat in the late 1920s and early 1930s.
Kipling died in 1936 and his ashes were interred in Poet's Corner in Westminster Abbey, in the company of other luminaries of British literature including Geoffrey Chaucer, Edmund Spenser, Charles Dickens, Thomas Hardy, and Alfred Lord Tennyson.
Samuel S. McClure (18570-1949) and Herbert Henry McClure (died 1938) were cousins and members of a publishing family, who founded the first American newspaper syndicate. Together they lauinched and/or supported numerous authors including Willa Cather, Booth Tarkington, Sir Arthur Conan Doyle, and Charles Dana Gibson. H.H. McClure counted Kipling amond his personal friends. E.W. (Ernest Walter) Martindell (1873-1951) was a British lawyer, member of the Royal Anthropological Institute, and Kipling's first bibliographer. No information can be found about Alan D. Wilson.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Rudyard Kipling Collection contains the papers of the British author, novelist, poet, and journalist, as well as three small collections of Kipling material formerly owned by H.H. and S.S. McClure, E.W. Martindell, and Alan D. Wilson.
Correspondence contains more than 950 items, both incoming and outgoing, with the vast majority from Kipling. Some items were written by his secretaries on his behalf. Correspondents include publishers and editors (H.H. and S.S. McClure, Doubleday), other authors (Somerset Maugham, Frederick W. Childs) collaborators (Louise Sington, who set some of Kipling's verse to music), and relatives (aunts, uncles, cousins). There is also some correspondence of Kipling's close family (wife, parents, children) and a small amount of correspondence between third parties.
Writings include Kipling's prose, speeches, verse and dramatic works, and so on. Formats include manuscript (handwritten and typed), proofs, galleys, and published versions. KpR numbers in this section refer to those assigned by Barbara Rosenbaum in the Index of English Literary Manuscripts (London; New York: Mansell, c1990, Vol. 4, pt. 2).
Memorabilia consists of legal material, photographs, and portraits and caricatures. Of particular interest is a power of attorney concerning the estate of Cecil John Rhodes, British politician and South African Prime Minister for whom Rhodesia was named.
Printed material includes clippings about Kipling and miscellaneous items such as dealer catalogues, and writings by others about Kipling. Published editions originally in this series have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging; a list of titles is retained in the inventory.
Miscellany includes bookplates, Kipling's pipe and typewriter, several scrapbooks, and assorted other items. There is also a printed meeting notice listing Kipling as an honorary member of Masonic Authors Lodge No. 3456.
The McClure collection contains a few items of correspondence, writings (one item by Kipling, the rest by McClure), some notes on Kipling's lawsuit against Putnam, and memorabilia (clippings, photographs, etc).
The E.W. Martindell collection contains one letter, a folder of 29 uncollected Kipling verses, and a folder of clippings with a short explanatory piece by Martindell.
The Alan D. Wilson collection, the largest of the three private collections included here, consists of correspondence (one item is from Kipling and one from his secretary; the rest are to/from others), several pieces of writing about Kipling (most are by Lloyd H, Chandler), and some personal memorabilia of Wilson's
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged by correspondent's name. Correspondence of his close family (wife, children, parents) is arranged by family member. Third party (neither from nor to Kipling) is arranged alphabetically by sender. Writings and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by type. The three smaller collections are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Separated Material
Published editions of Kipling's work, and a few other published items, have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging, as noted in the inventory below. Please refer to to locate these items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- British; Literature -- Children's; Arkwright, John S. (John Stanhope), 1872-1954.; Ballard, Ellis Ames, 1861-1938.; Barton, D. Plunket (Dunbar Plunket), Sir, 1853-1937.; Bensusan, S. L. (Samuel Levy), 1872-1958.; Besant, Walter, 1836-1901.; Bisland, Elizabeth, 1861-1929.; Blackburn, Vernon, 1866-1907.; Blanchan, Neltje, 1865-1918.; Blumenfeld, Ralph D. (Ralph David), 1864-1948.; Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930.; Booth, J. B. (John Bennion), 1880-1961.; Boothby, Guy, 1867-1905.; Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936.; Buckle, George Earle, 1854-1935.; Bullen, Frank Thomas, 1857-1915.; Burlingame, Edward L. (Edward Livermore), 1848-1922.; Chandler, Lloyd H. (Lloyd Horwitz), 1869-1947.; Chappell, Henry, 1871-; Cherry-Garrard, Apsley, 1886-1959.; Childs, F. W. (Frederick W.), 1849-1946.; Colvin, Ian Duncan, 1877-1938.; Curties, Arthur William Statter, -1943.; Dawson, Bertrand Edward Dawson, Viscount, -1945.; Dodge, Mary Mapes, 1830-1905.; Drury, W. P. (William Price), 1861-1949.; Farrere, Claude, 1876-1957.; Feilden, H. W. (Henry Wemyss), 1838-1921.; Flight, Claude, 1881-1955.; Frazer, James George, 1854-1941.; Frewen, Moreton, 1853-1924.; Fry, O. A. (Oliver Armstrong), 1855-1931.; Gollancz, Israel, 1864-1930.; Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928.; Grosvenor, Caroline, 1858-1940.; Gurlitz, Augustus T., 1842-1928.; Gurney, J. H. (John Henry), 1848-1922.; Gwynne, Roland Vaughan.; Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903.; Hodgson, W. Earl (William Earl), -1910.; Johnson, Charles Plumptre, 1853-1938.; Keyes, Roger, 1872-1945.; Kipling, Caroline, 1865-1939.; Kipling, Elsie.; Kipling, John Lockwood, 1837-1911.; Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936.; Lawrence, T. E. (Thomas Edward), 1888-1935.; Lawrence, Walter R. (Walter Roper), Sir, 1857-1940.; Legouis, Emile, 1861-1937.; Lessing, Bruno, 1870-1940.; Low, Sidney, Sir, 1857-1932.; Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1868-1938.; Mais, S. P. B. (Stuart Petre Brodie), 1885-1975.; Marconi, Guglielmo, 1874-1937.; Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1874-1965.; McClure, H. H.; McClure, S. S. (Samuel Sidney), 1857-1949.; Milner, Violet Georgina Milner, Viscountess, 1872-1958.; Milner, Alfred Milner, Viscount, 1854-1925.; Parkin, George R. (George Robert), 1846-1922.; Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911.; Rawlinson, A. R.; Rhodes, Cecil, 1853-1902.; Robinson, Harry Perry, 1859-1930.; Sington, Louise.; Tallents, Stephen, 1884-1958.; Tesla, Nikola, 1856-1943.; Tregaskis, James, 1850-1926.; Young, Filson, 1876-1938.; D. Appleton and Company.; Freemasons. -- Authors' Lodge No. 3456 (London, England); S.S. McClure Company (New York, N.Y.); Dramatists, English.; English literature.; English poetry.; English literature -- 19th century.; English literature -- 20th century.; English literature -- Illustrations.; Journalists -- England.; Novelists, English.; Poets, English.; War stories, English.; Articles.; Books.; Caricatures.; Catalogs (documents); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Galley proofs.; Illustrations.; Juvenilia.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Poems.; Proofs (printed matter); Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Telegrams.; Authors.; Dramatists.; Novelists.; Journalists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Bulk of collection purchased from various dealers, starting in 1950.
Some items, gift of William Pearson Tolley, David J. Holmes, and Lisa Lewis.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Actors' Orphanage, 1923; signed by Gerald du Maurier (Box 1)
  - Adam, Pearl [Mrs. George], 1920; 1926-1931 (Box 1)
  - Adee, Mr. [Alvey?], 1897 (Box 1)
  - Alden, P. M., 1916 (Box 1)
  - Aldous, B. E., 1932 (Box 1)
  - Allen, George, 1897 (Box 1)
  - Arkwright, John S., 1901 (Box 1)
  - Armitage, Mrs., 1898; 1908 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Authors, 1893 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, George, 1904-1906; 1913 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Mr., 1916 (Box 1)
  - Barr, Robert [aka Luke Sharp], 1896 (Box 1)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Barr, Robert.
  - Barton, Plunket, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Baskerfield, William V., 1933; 1935; letters relate to duties as chauffeur (Box 1)
  - Beaman, A. G., 1933 (Box 1)
  - Beauchamp, Earl [William Lygon], 1927 (Box 1)
  - Becher, Mrs., 1932 (Box 1)
  - Beckett, Captain, 1915 (Box 1)
  - Beith, J. H. [John Hay], 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Fitzroy, 1890-1881 (Box 1)
  - Belt, Anthony, 1913; undated (Box 1)
  - Bensusan, S. L. (Samuel Levy), 1913; 1926-1935 (Box 1)
  - Bentley, Richard, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Berthout, Leon, 1916 (Box 1)
  - Besant, Walter, 1898 (Box 1)
  - Bisland, Elizabeth, [1890] (Box 1)
  - Black, [Steven William?], 1908 (Box 1)
  - Black, Mrs., 1912 (Box 1)
  - Blackburn, Vernon, [1899] (Box 1)
  - Blankenberg, [R.A.?], 1920 (Box 1)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Jan Christiaan Smuts.
  - Blanchan, Neltje, See [Doubleday], Nelli.
  - Block, Rudolph Edgar, See [Lessing, Bruno].
  - Blogg, Miss, [1897] (Box 1)
  - Blumenfeld, [Ralph D.?], 1911; 1918 (Box 1)
  - Blyth, Lord, 1912; 1918,; 1920 (Box 1)
  - Bok, Edward William, 1893; 1902-1915,; 1918,; 1920,; 1923-1925,; 1935,; undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Booth, John Bennion, 1927; 1934-1935; includes 1 letter written by Kipling's secretary, C.L. Nicholson (Box 1)
  - Boothby, Guy Newll, 1893; 1901 (Box 1)
  - Boothby, Geoffrey, 1921; 1927 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, A. O., 1931 (Box 1)
  - Brand, Mr., 1908 (Box 1)
  - Braver, Miss, undated (Box 1)
  - Brentanos, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Bres, Dr. Pierre and Madame, 1934-1936 (Box 1)
  - Brisbane, Arthur, 1899 (Box 1)
  - British Empire League, 1899 (Box 1)
  - Bruce, A. Selwyn, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Buckle, George Earle, 1897; 1902,; undated; includes one item written to Mrs. Buckle, which would have been his first wife, Alicia Isobel Payn (Box 1)
  - Bullen, [Frank Thomas], 1898; 1914; includes typescripts of the 1898 letters (Box 1)
  - Burlingame, [Edward L.], 1894; 1897; includes cover layout of 1894 issue in which article appeared, original watercolor by Howard Pyle; one item (1897) letter is photocopy of original letter in Burlingame Family Papers at SU (Box 1)
  - Burne, C. V., 1917 (Box 1)
  - Byng, Lady [Marie Evelyn, Viscountess Byng of Vimy?], undated (Box 1)
  - Camp, E. M., 1894 (Box 1)
  - Canney, Leigh, 1903 (Box 1)
  - Capel Cure, E., 1916 (Box 1)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, [1899?]; written by someone on Carnegie's staff conveying a personal note from him to Kipling (Box 1)
  - Cecil, Lady Edward [Violet Georgina], 1902; 1908-1917; 4 folders (Box 1)
    Following her second marriage, Lady Cecil became Viscountess Milner; thus, see also Milner, Lady Alfred.
  - Chandler, Lloyd H., 1929-1930; photocopies of originals in the Alan D. Wilson material (see below) (Box 1)
    See also Correspondence: Third party (below); there are also numerous Chandler items in the Alan D. Wilson material (below).
  - Chapman, Major, [1910?] (Box 2)
  - Chappell, H. [Henry], 1917-1918; known as the 'Bath Railway Poet' (Box 2)
  - Cherry-Gararrd, Apsley, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Childs, Mr. and Mrs., 1900; authors of The Ancients Abroad in 1896, thus presumably Frederick W. Childs (Box 2)
  - Clark, [ ], 1922; 1926; letters addressed variously to "Lady", "Mrs.", and "Major Hartley", about their son's book on Afghan carpets (Box 2)
  - Colvin, Ian D., 1909-1913; 1916-1922,; 1933,; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Conant, Miss, 1895 (Box 2)
  - Connabeer, A. J., 1908 (Box 2)
  - Cooke, J. H. Corpl., 1893 (Box 2)
  - Cope, Mr., 1906 (Box 2)
  - Creighton, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Curties, Dr. [Arthur William Statter], 1913; 1926-1930,; 1934,; undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
    See also Correspondence: Family: Kipling, Caroline (wife).
  - Cushing, J., 1922 (Box 2)
  - Customs Officer, 1934 (Box 2)
  - D. Appleton and Company, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Davis, Mr. [Richard Harding?], 1892 (Box 2)
  - Dawson, Sir Bertrand, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Dixon-Spain, Rev. T., 1913 (Box 2)
  - Dodge, Mary Mapes, 1894; 1897 (Box 2)
  - Doubleday, Nelli [Mrs. Frank N.], 1905 (Box 2)
  - Drury, Col. W. P., 1925 (Box 2)
  - Dufferin, Lord, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Edmonds, P. N., 1918 (Box 2)
  - Edwards, R. W. K., 1913 (Box 2)
  - [Elliott & Fry], [1894] (Box 2)
  - Ensor, Miss [Mary C.], 1911 (Box 2)
  - Falconer, Bruce M., 1901 (Box 2)
  - Farrère, [Claude], 1933 (Box 2)
  - Feilden, Henry Wemyss, 1904-1914; 1918-1920; 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Feilden, Henry Wemyss, 1921; 1932,; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Fiennes, [ ], 1923 (Box 3)
  - Fletcher, Sir Henry, 1900 (Box 3)
  - Flight, Claude, 1906-1909; artist (Box 3)
  - Flint, Henry N., 1936; written by Kipling's secretary, C.L. Nicholson (Box 3)
  - Foster, A. T., 1924 (Box 3)
  - Fraser, [William A.?], [1897?]; undated (Box 3)
  - Frazer, Sir James George, 1923 (Box 3)
  - French, W., 1900 (Box 3)
  - Frere-Reeves, A. S. [Alexander Stuart], 1925; 1927-1934,; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Frewen, Moreton, 1912; 1914,; 1918,; undated (Box 3)
  - Frost, E. Elliott, 1906; photocopy; original is cataloged (Box 3)
  - Frost, John W. [son-in-law of Augustus T. Gurlitz], 1929 (Box 3)
  - Fry, Oliver Armstrong, 1899 (Box 3)
  - Furlong, Gerald, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Garlick, Mr., 1908 (Box 3)
  - Gilder, [R.W.], 1892 (Box 3)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Gilder, R.W.
  - Gill, Mr., 1917 (Box 3)
  - Gilmour [Gilmore?], Mr., 1919 (Box 3)
  - Glossop, Miss, undated (Box 3)
  - Gollancz, [Israel], 1917 (Box 3)
  - Goodchild, Mr., undated; 4 telegraph messages to a Mr. Goodchild in Springfield, MA (Box 3)
  - Gosse, Edmund, 1890; includes book cover that held the letter (Box 3)
  - Grandande, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Grayson, Tristram, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Greely, H. W., 1899 (Box 3)
  - Grosvenor, [Caroline], undated (Box 3)
  - Gubbins, J. G., 1925 (Box 3)
  - Guitous Stores, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Gurlitz, Augustus, 1899-1904; undated; includes 2 empty envelopes (Box 3)
    See also Correspondence: Family, under both Caroline and John Lockwood; and Correspondence: Third party: Watt, A.P.
  - Gurney, J. H. [John Henry], 1911 (Box 3)
  - Guthrie, Mrs., 1901 (Box 3)
  - Gwynne, Roland [Vaughan], 1930-1935 (Box 3)
  - Haines, Reginald, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Hanlon, Elizabeth (Betty), 1930 (Box 3)
  - Harding, W. J., 1912 (Box 3)
  - Hargreaves, Mr., 1914 (Box 3)
  - Hay, Ian, See Beith, J. H. [John Hay].
  - Heard, General G. S., 1928 (Box 3)
  - Heathcote, 1901 (Box 3)
  - Henley, [William Ernest], 1890; 1892,; undated (Box 3)
  - [Herbert], Stephen, 1893 (Box 3)
  - Heron-Maxwell, Mrs., 1926 (Box 3)
  - Hodgson, [William] Earl, 1909 (Box 3)
  - Hodgson, J. E., 1921 (Box 3)
  - Hodson, [Leonard James], 1915; 1921 (Box 3)
  - Holland, T. [?], 1907 (Box 3)
  - Hooper, G., 1889 (Box 3)
  - Hooper, Maggie, [1910] (Box 3)
  - Hunt, [A.?], 1905; 1928,; undated; one item is a photocopy; original is tipped into The Five Nations, which has been cataloged (Box 3)
  - Hunting, H. A., Sub-Lt., 1922 (Box 3)
  - Huth, Captain, 1915 (Box 3)
  - Jacobs, Joseph, 1909 (Box 3)
  - James, F. E., 1902 (Box 3)
  - Janeway, Edward G., 1899; undated; notes written about Kipling's health during his bout with pneumonia (Box 3)
  - Jefferson, Miss, 1918 (Box 3)
  - Jillbert, [?], 1890 (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Charles P. [Plumptre], 1922 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, R. M., 1912 (Box 4)
  - Johnson, [Robert U.], 1935 (Box 4)
  - Kaye, W. J., 1920 (Box 4)
  - Kell, Copeland, [1899]; undated (Box 4)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Kell, Copeland.
  - Kett, R., 1929 (Box 4)
  - Keyes, Sir Roger, 1920; 1925,; 1928 (Box 4)
  - Klingel, M. P., 1927 (Box 4)
  - Larkin, Mr. [Peter Charles], 1922; 1928 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, Neville, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, Miss T., 1935 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, T. E., 1919; 1922 (Box 4)
  - Lawrence, Walter, 1897-1900; 1904,; 1928 (Box 4)
  - Le Blond, Mrs. [Elizabeth Hawkins-Whitshed?], 1924 (Box 4)
  - Lee, John S., 1891 (Box 4)
  - Legal and Commercial Insurance Co. Ltd., 1911 (Box 4)
  - Legouis, Emile, 1922 (Box 4)
  - Leonard, Mr. and Mrs., 1904-1905; 1908,; 1910 (Box 4)
  - [Lessing, Bruno], 1898 (Box 4)
  - Levy, Monsieur, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Randolph, 1922 (Box 4)
  - L'Hopital, Captain, 1927 (Box 4)
  - Livingston, Mrs. Luther S. [Flora V.], 1935 (Box 4)
    See also and Correspondence: Third party: Livingston, Flora V. and Alan D. Wilson collection: Correspondence.
  - Loraine, Mr., 1913 (Box 4)
  - Low, [Morgens], undated (Box 4)
  - Low, Peter, 1899 (Box 4)
  - Low, Sir Sidney, 1922 (Box 4)
  - Lucas, E. V., 1930; 1932 (Box 4)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Lucas, E.V.
  - Lyons, Arthur, 1922 (Box 4)
  - MacAlister, Ian, 1931 (Box 4)
  - MacColl, Norman, 1891 (Box 4)
  - Mahon, Captain R. F. Haviland, 1924 (Box 4)
  - Mais, S.P.B. [Stuart Petre Brodie], 1934 (Box 4)
  - Malleson, [R.], 1905 (Box 4)
  - Marconi, G., 1911 (Box 4)
  - Martyn-Linnington, [ ], 1925 (Box 4)
  - Massey, Major C.F., 1910 (Box 4)
  - Matheson, G., 1901 (Box 4)
  - Matheson, Mr., 1902 (Box 4)
  - Maugham, Somerset, 1928 (Box 4)
  - Maury, Miss, 1901 (Box 4)
  - Mayor of Bath, 1923 (Box 4)
  - McCarthy, M.J.F., 1914 (Box 4)
  - McClure, Harry H. [cousin and employee of S. S. McClure at Doubleday], 1896; 1899-1901,; 1907,; 1920,; 1932,; undated; includes several letters written by Kipling's secretary, Sara Anderson, as well as 3 telegrams sent by Kipling but signed as someone else, as a joke; 2 folders (Box 4)
    See also Correspondence: Third party in general, including Anna S. Balestier, Ellis Ames Ballard, Robert Barr, Kell Copeland, Frank N. Doubleday, Frank, Charles Eliot Norton, and J.B. Pond.
  - McClure, S. [Samuel Sidney], 1893; 1899 (Box 4)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: R.W. Gilder.
  - Medley, Mr., 1925 (Box 4)
  - Melville, D.O., 1894 (Box 4)
  - Melville, George W., 1894 (Box 4)
  - Methuen, Lady [Emily Caroline], 1925 (Box 4)
  - Methuen, Sir Algernon, 1905; 1908,; 1913 (Box 4)
  - Mildmay, St. John, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Milner, Lady Alfred (Violet Georgina, Viscountess Milner), 1922-1933; 3 folders (Box 4)
    See also Cecil, Lady Edward.
  - Milner, Lord Alfred (Viscount Milner), 1911; [1914],; 1918,; 1921; one item is a copy; original in Bodleian Library (Box 4)
  - Mineloz, H., 1897 (Box 4)
  - Minnigerode, F.L., 1926 (Box 4)
  - Mirrielees, [Sir Frederick James], 1900 (Box 4)
  - Mohommed, Sher, 1911 (Box 4)
  - Monroe, Captain F., 1917 (Box 4)
  - Montague, Albert E., 1923 (Box 4)
  - Moreton, T.W.E., 1923; 1927,; 1935 (Box 4)
  - Moroney, Herman, 1911 (Box 4)
    See also Writings: Miscellany: Royal Automobile Club Touring Report.
  - Morrison, W.R., 1930; 1934 (Box 4)
  - Mortimer, Charles G., 1924-1927; some responses written by Kipling's secretary, M.E. Walford (Box 5)
  - Murray, Douglas, 1907 (Box 5)
  - Nesbit, Miss, 1896 (Box 5)
  - Nesbitt, Mrs., 1905 (Box 5)
  - New York Press, 1899 (Box 5)
  - Nicholson, Mrs. T.J.B., 1907 (Box 5)
  - Noble, Edward, 1905 (Box 5)
  - Norton, Mr. [Charles Eliot], 1895; includes clipping that looks like it came from a more recent publication (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Norton, Charles Eliot.
  - Nott, Miss M., 1916 (Box 5)
  - Nourse, Mr. [J.L.], 1895 (Box 5)
  - Paget, Stephen, 1912 (Box 5)
  - Paine, Mr., 1910 (Box 5)
  - Parkin, Dr. [Sir George Robert], 1918 (Box 5)
  - Paton, J.L., 1923 (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Lucy W., 1909 (Box 5)
  - Pegram, Henry, 1907 (Box 5)
  - Perry, Private, 1915; includes one written by Kipling's secretary, M. Chamberlain (Box 5)
  - Phillips, [W.] Hallett, 1895; bound in slipcase (Box 5)
  - Pollock [Poro?], Lady, [Aug 1891?] (Box 5)
  - Poore, Lady [Ida Margaret], 1922 (Box 5)
  - Poynter, Agnes Macdonald ("Dear Auntie"), 1890 (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Poynter, Agnes Macdonald.
  - Poynter, Ambrose [Kipling's cousin] ("Dear Ambo"), 1902 (Box 5)
  - Poynter, Hugh [Kipling's cousin], 1913 (Box 5)
  - [Poysen, Arthur], 1911 (Box 5)
  - Pyle, Howard, See Burlingame, [Edward L.].